<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Mountain Hydrology Research Group</title>
    <link>https://mountain-hydrology.github.io/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://mountain-hydrology.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 11:25:57 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://mountain-hydrology.github.io/media/icon_hu5d4c7442664073cb1a48933bbcbba29d_19758_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://mountain-hydrology.github.io/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantify post-fire impacts</title>
      <link>https://mountain-hydrology.github.io/project/wildfire/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 11:25:57 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mountain-hydrology.github.io/project/wildfire/</guid>
      <description>&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;PI&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Siwei He&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Period&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2022-08 to 2023-01&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, the impact of wildfires on the land-surface biogeophysical properties, such as soil
hydraulic conductivity and vegetation type, was identified and parameterized.
Then, the impact of post-wildfire conditions on weather forecasting was investigated&lt;br&gt;
by considering post-wildfire land-surface conditions in the Weather Research and Forecasting (WRF) model.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Characterizing the afternoon-to-evening transition</title>
      <link>https://mountain-hydrology.github.io/project/arm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 11:25:57 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mountain-hydrology.github.io/project/arm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;PI&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;David D Turner&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Period&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2020-03 to 2022-07&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project aimed to improve our understanding of the complex land-atmosphere processes
and their interaction during the afternoon to evening transition (AET).
In particular, we proposed to use a combination of land surface and profiling
observations together and mesoscale model simulations to better understand how the
surface energy balance and lower atmosphere evolve during the AET.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through this project, the performance of version 4 of the NOAA High-Resolution Rapid
Refresh (HRRR) numerical weather prediction model for near-surface variables,
including wind, humidity, temperature, surface latent and sensible fluxes, and
longwave and shortwave radiative fluxes, was examined over the Atmospheric Radiation
Measurement (ARM) Southern Great Plains (SGP) region.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project also investigated the processes leading to the water vapor increase and
the impacts of the land cover and horizontal advection on the water vapor increase
through a single column model. This study also found that land cover can affect the
onset of water vapor increase since different land covers may have different Bowen ratios.
Water vapor increases earlier for land cover conditions that have small Bowen ratio,
relative to larger Bowen ratio values.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coupling snow sub-grid variability model into a land-surface model</title>
      <link>https://mountain-hydrology.github.io/project/nrc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 10:56:59 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mountain-hydrology.github.io/project/nrc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;PI&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Siwei He&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Period&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2018-08 to 2020-02&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project aimed to solve the spatial variability of snow depth
problem in the Earth system modeling. A snow model for representing sub-grid
variability of snow depth was coupled into the Rapid Update Cycle Land
Surface Model (RUC LSM), and its impacts on the LSM was evaluated.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wyoming Center for Environmental Hydrology and Geophysics (WyCEHG)</title>
      <link>https://mountain-hydrology.github.io/project/wycehg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 10:49:25 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mountain-hydrology.github.io/project/wycehg/</guid>
      <description>&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;PI&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Steve Holbrook, Scott N Miller, Ginger Paige&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Period&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2014-09 to 2017-12&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Wyoming Center for Environmental Hydrology and Geophysics (WyCEHG) was established
in July 2012 with a NSF grant. The goal of WyCEHG is to establish a center of
excellence in environmental hydrology and hydrogeophysics. WyCEHG uses surface and
subsurface hydrological models to link surface and groundwater.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
